mailup.com 2019-09-23

# Privacy Policy | MailUp

### 1\. Data Controller

We at MailUp S.p.A. an email marketing company with registered office in Viale F. Restelli 1, 20124 Milan, Italy (the “ **Company** ”, “ **MailUp** ”, “ **We** ” or the “ **Controller** ”) ensure compliance with privacy regulations by providing the following information on the processing of data that is received or in any case collected while you browse our Website or use our Platform.

### 2\. Definitions

In this privacy policy, these terms have the following meanings:

**Application(s)** : programme created by MailUp with the aim of implementing one or more functions, services or tools which may be selected upon request by the user.

**Client(s)** : means any person or entity that is registered with us to use our Platform.

**Event(s)** : means any workshop, professional training session, thematic event promoted or sponsored by MailUp.

**List(s) (or Mailing List/Environments)** : means an independent set of recipients uploaded by a Client and managed on our Platform. Each recipient consists of, at least, an email address or a mobile number. The Client may choose to upload additional information related to those recipients (e.g. name, surname, street address) if needed.

**Platform** : an online digital platform accessible through the Internet via the modality “Software As A Service”. It enables Clients to directly manage marketing campaigns and on-line communications in general using different messaging channels (email, sms, Social Networks);

**Personal Data** : means any information that identifies or can be used to identify a Client or a User, directly or indirectly (e.g. first name and surname, date of birth, email address).

**User(s)** : means any person who visits this Website, uses our Applications and take part in an Event.

**Website(s)** : means [www.mailup.com](https://www.mailup.com/)

### 3\. Privacy for Clients

This section applies to the Personal Data we collect and process as Data Controller from a Client or potential Client through the provision of the Platform. If you are not a Client, please read the Users section of this policy.

Please note that we process your Mailing List as Data Processor in accordance with instructions defined in Section 2.3 of our [Platform License Agreement](https://www.mailup.com/platform-license-agreement/).

#### What Personal Data we collect

_Personal Data provide by you in the course of engaging with our Platform._

Certain parts of our Website may ask you to provide Personal Data voluntarily in order to sign up for an account:

  1. registration information (e.g. your name, email address, username, password, company name, address); and
  2. billing information (e.g. billing address).

_Personal Data we collect automatically when you use our Platform._

When you use the Platform we may collect such information:

  1. device information you use to access the Platform (e.g. IP address, your operating system, your browser ID);
  2. log data (e.g. log files that record data each time a device accesses our web servers and those log files contain data about the nature of each access, including originating IP addresses);
  3. Platform usage data (e.g. dates and times you access the Platform and your browsing activities); and
  4. information regarding the metrics of the Platform (e.g. delivery rate, open rate, click rate).

_Personal Data we collect automatically when we send you emails and formal notices._

We use tracking systems such as pixel and web beacons to allow us to know whether a message sent by MailUp to a Client was read by a Client, whether any hyperlink in a message was clicked by the Client, record the IP address and the type of browser/agent used to perform that activity.

#### How we use your Personal Data

We use and disclose your Personal Data in order to:

  1. supply, improve and support the Platform;
  2. make research and analysis on the Platform;
  3. ask you a feedback and to verify your experience using the Platform;
  4. enforce compliance with our Platform License Agreement;
  5. protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized or illegal activity;
  6. promote our services to you and develop additional offers;
  7. Send you invoices or notices;
  8. Comply with a legal obligation or respond to lawful requests by public authorities;
  9. Communicate directly with you, to respond to your inquiries or otherwise, to provide customer support.

#### Which is the legal grounds for the processing

The legal ground for the processing of Personal Data provided by you or collected by us via the notices and emails sent to you is the execution of a contract to which you are a party or the execution of pre-contractual measures adopted upon requests of the same.

The legal basis of the processing of Personal Data you voluntarily provide to ask you a feedback and verify your experience using the Platform is the legitimate interest in conducting research and analysis on our Platform.

The legal ground for the processing of the Personal Data we collect automatically when you use our Platform is legitimate interest to improve the user experience of the Platform, to facilitate research and analysis of the Platform, and to the prevention of frauds, criminal acts or other threats to security.

### 4\. Privacy for Users

This section applies to Personal Data that we collect and process as data Controller through our Website and our Applications.

#### What Personal Data we collect

_Personal Data we collect automatically when you use the Website or our Applications and when you are signed up for the Event._

The information systems and the software used for this Website, for the Applications and the Events acquire, during their normal use, certain personal data which is implicitly transferred while using Internet communication protocols (such as, for example, domain names, IP addresses, operating system used, type of device and browser used in the connection).

_Personal Data you provide to us on the Website, Applications or in any Event’s registration._

Certain parts of our Website, Applications or Event’s registration form may ask you to provide Personal Data voluntarily in order to sign up for a trial account, apply for a job with MailUp, for taking part in any Event or otherwise submit inquiries to us.

_Personal Data we collect automatically when we send you emails and newsletters._

We use tracking systems such as pixel and web beacons to allows us to know whether a message sent by MailUp to a User was read by a User, whether any hyperlink in a message was clicked by the User, record the IP address and the type of browser/agent used to perform that activity.

#### How we use your personal information

We use and disclose your Personal Data in order to:

  1. collect anonymous statistical information on the use of the site to better understand the preferences of our Users;
  2. provide, operate, optimize, and maintain our Website and manage its security;
  3. respond to your inquiries and requests made through the Website;
  4. set up online accounts or registered you for the Event;
  5. send newsletters, marketing materials, updates on our activities, Events you are signed up and new postings on our blog; promotional notices on event invites, training, webinars, special promotions;
  6. if you send us your curriculum vitae, exclusively for the selection process.

#### Which is the legal grounds for the processing

The legal ground for processing of the Personal Data collected automatically, depending on the circumstances, is: 

  1. legitimate interest to render the Website’s and Applications’ features functional following the user’s access;
  2. consent freely given according to our Cookie Statement.; 
  3. the legitimate interest of MailUp in sending you communications similar to the content you use through our Applications or related to the Events you are signed up or similar to them.

The legal ground for processing of the Personal Data you provide to us deliberately or we collect through the emails and newsletters sent to you, depending on the circumstances, is:

  1. consent freely given and any refusal shall make it impossible for us to send you any newsletters, advertising materials, invites to our events and initiatives and to provide you special promotions;
  2. the execution of a contract to which you are a party or the execution of pre-contractual measures adopted upon requests of the same;
  3. the legitimate interest of MailUp in sending you communications similar to the content you use through our Applications or Events.

### 5\. Common provisions

#### Which are our security measures

We process your Personal Data using electronic, or in any case, automated, computer and telematic, or manual methods that are logically strictly related to the purpose for which such data was collected, and in any case, in a manner to guarantee the security of the same. For further information about our security practices, please see our Security page [here](https://www.mailup.com/gdpr-infrastructure/).

#### How long do we retain your Personal Data

We store your Personal Data for the term that is strictly necessary for the management of the purposes for which Personal Data was collected, in compliance with the law in force and the legal obligations. 

In any case, MailUp has enacted practices that prohibit the storage of Personal Data for an undetermined period of time and therefore limits the storage term in compliance with the principle of minimising data processing. 

#### Persons authorised to process data, data processors and disclosing of data

Your Personal Data are processed by persons working within MailUp appointed and authorised for this end. If necessary or fundamental to execute the indicated purposes, we may share your Personal Data with external third-party Processors and more specifically: companies belonging to our corporate group; individuals, companies, associations or groups of professionals that provide assistance and advice to our Company; companies, entities or associations that provide services connected and instrumental to carrying out the above-mentioned purposes (market analysis and research, management of payments through credit cards, information system management). Having received specific consent, we may also transfer Personal Data abroad, to companies both belonging or not belonging to our corporate group, including countries outside the European Union, in the form and manner envisaged in the current law, guaranteeing, nevertheless, an adequate level of protection. In any case, we will never disseminate Personal Data.

#### Which are your rights

You can access, object to the processing or request the erasure, the modification or the updating of all the Personal Data collected by MailUp, at any time, by exercising the right to limit the data processing and the movement of data, by sending an email to: [privacy@mailup.com](mailto:privacy@mailup.com)

If we have collected and processed your Personal Data with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. 

If you are a Client, you can manage many of your individual account and profile settings within the dashboard provided through the Platform. 

You have also the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. Contact details for data protection authorities in the EEA are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).

#### Data Privacy Officer

We appointed a Data Privacy Officer, who may be contacted via the following email: [dpo@mailup.com](mailto:dpo@mailup.com)

Last update: 2nd September 2019
